Jennifer Cooper

UX Researcher & Designer

CONTACT

-

jennifercooper.design



hello@jennifercooper.design



+1 925 482 7312



/jennifercooperdesign

I am a Principal User Experience Researcher and Designer whose key interests lie in technically focused research and concept development, with 12+ years experience in research and design, and expertise in UX, Human Factors, and Systems Engineering. My work focuses on the intersection of humans and technology, developing futures based on current markets and constraints. I enjoy facilitating customer engagements and leading product design, working with teams and experts to research new technologies and develop new products.

CAREER

Principal Designer

Oct 2018-Present Skylo Technologies, USA Currently leading all product and marketing design for a series A/B start up. Partnering with leadership and product teams to define the customer service model, attract investment interest, develop the platform experience, and onboard initial customers.

Staff UX Designer

June 2018-Oct 2018 GE Digital, USA Led design for OPM (Operations Performance Management) tools, facilitating alignment across GE, responsible for research and design strategy and implementation for several business units.

Sr UX Designer

2016-June 2018 GE Digital, USA Led research and concept design for PaaS (Platform as a Service) and APM (Asset Performance Management) tools for businesses in the industrial internet space.

UX Designer

2014-2016 GE Digital, USA Led research, HMI design and prototyping for future flight deck research programs, using emerging interface technologies and practices. Led customer engagements and design projects for prototype aviation enterprise products.

UX Designer

2012-2013 GE Aviation, USA Applied UX Lean Design Processes to design operations and asset optimization tools for airlines, airports and OEMs. Drove the growth of GE Design by evangelizing design thinking techniques.

Systems Engineer

2009-2012 GE Aviation, UK Research and development for the future of flight deck systems, emerging technologies and SPO (Single Pilot Operations). Symbology and use case specialist for onboard embedded Systems.

Systems Eng. Grad

2007-2009 GE Aviation, UK 2-year graduate program designed to accelerate leadership growth. Specialized in onboard embedded military and civil flight deck systems, pilot operations and HMI symbology.

EDUCATION

MEng Aerospace Engineering

University of Sheffield, UK

EXPERIENCES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Master of Ceremonies @ 'Primer' 2017 & 2018 Speaker @ SXSW Eco 2016: 'Alternative Futures that Matter' Patents Pending and Awarded in Aviation and technology:

20180032073; 20170345318; 20170210484; 20130245860; 20160307100